# SNEHIL KUMAR SINHA

#### **Operations Associate**

Hi, I am an Operations Team Member with 1+ years of experience in mortgage & commercial lending, servicing & banking operations. Underwritten commercial loans for small & mid-size businesses under Paycheck Protection Program. Responsible for reviewing, analyzing, labelling and managing loan documents in the bank's database. Well focused and dedicated when managing workloads, prioritizing efficiency to accomplish tasks before deadlines. Effective in working as a team, with good communication skills.



✓ snehilkumar.sinha@gmail.com

0

Bengaluru, India

#### . +91-7979020422

in linkedin.com/in/snehil-kumar-sinha-95ab66161

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Operations Team Member**

BA Continuum India Pvt. Ltd. (Bank of America Corporation)

10/2020 - Present

Gandhinagar, Gujarat

Tasks/Achievements

- Working in the Loan Origination & Consumer Lending line of business. Responsible for reviewing, analyzing, labelling and uploading loan and investment documents to the database. Meeting and exceeding KPIs on a monthly basis.
- Also working in the Mortgage Servicing Operations(MSO) team. Delivering optimum servicing on home loans and responsible for responding to customers, investors & third party's loan related queries.
- Ensuring timely delivery of service in order to meet SLAs along with maintaining accuracy of above 99.99%.
- Performed commercial loan underwriting for small & midsize businesses under Paycheck Protection Program.
  Reviewed first draw and second draw loan applications, verified payroll and tax return documents to make decisions.
- For excellent process knowledge, was appointed as a Subject Matter Expert(SME) to train and assist associates in Payoff Demand process.
- Responsible to advise Front Line Manager (FLM) for process improvement and automation on freeform letters.

## INTERNSHIPS

Boston Consulting Group - Business Consultant Trainee (04/2020 - 05/2020)

 Performed market research & data analysis in order to prepare business reports in project of a Singapore based Smartphone Leasing firm.

## **EDUCATION**

**Bachelor of Business Administration (Hons.)**Siksha 'O' Anusandhan (Deemed to be University)

2017 - 2020 Bhubaneswar, India

**12th Intermediate**Doon Public School

**SKILLS** 

Strong Decision Maker

Team Player

Process Analysis

Quality Assurance

Time Management

Problem Solving

Asset Management

Risk Management

Attenion to Detail

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Programming Languages** 

C, R

Additional Tools

Advanced Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook, MySQL, R Studio

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

Business Analytics with Excel (01/2022 - 03/2022)

Customer Analytics in Business (03/2021 - 06/2021)

**LANGUAGES** 

English

Hindi

Professional Working Proficiency

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

**INTERESTS** 

Equity & Capital Market

Automobile Enthusiast

Travelling

2015 - 2016 Dhanbad, India